Hans Tanawi

Taipei, Taiwan | hanstanawi@gmail.com | +886987073094 | hanstanawi.com | Github | LinkedIn

Summary

I am a software engineer with **3 years** of experience in the software industry. My focus area for the past few years has been **frontend development** with **React** and **Next.js**, utilizing **TypeScript**. I am also skilled in backend development with **Node.js** and have experience using TypeScript in that context as well.

Professional Experience

Lumina 4K Al Webcam / Al powered 4K webcam to make remote work better Full Stack Engineer

Taipei, Taiwan

Nov 2021 - Present

- Lead the development of Lumina e-commerce landing page with **responsive design** using **React**, **TypeScript**, **Next.js**, and **TailwindCSS**. Successfully integrate Shopify API to ensure seamless e-commerce operations.
- Build and manage a backend **RESTful API** from the ground up, utilizing **Node.js**, **TypeScript**, **NestJS**, and **Prisma** as a foundation for the Lumina Studio application and **PostgreSQL** as database server.
- Improved landing page loading speed by applying techniques such as, code splitting, lazy loading, and image optimization, achieved a **20% improvement** in pagespeed score.
- Implement A/B testing on webpage content, utilizing Google Analytics and Amplitude to collect user analytics, resulting in 3% improvement on conversion rate.
- Utilize Jest and Supertest to implement unit and integrations, enhance code assurance and decrease the risk of bugs.
- Implement a **CI/CD** pipeline using **Github Actions** to automate the build, test, and deployment process to **Heroku**, resulting in faster feedback loops and increased productivity.

Molteo / a digital workspace for construction sites to manage projects and paperless billing

Germany (Remote)

Frontend Engineer

May 2020 – Nov 2021

- Developed and maintained modern, performant, and robust code of Molteo web application with **Vue**, **Vuex**, and **Vuetify**. Wrote E2E tests using **Cypress** to cover main usage scenarios.
- Led the development of Project History feature which allows companies to view and share projects with clients by building a new web platform using **Vue** and **TailwindCSS**, leading to **3+ construction companies** signing up with Molteo software.
- Applied a migration process on frontend codebase from **JavaScript** to **TypeScript** to enhance code quality, better development experience, and improve performance, leading to a **20% reduction** in bugs.
- Implemented a CI/CD pipeline using Gitlab CI to automate build, tests, and deployment process to AWS S3, resulting in increased productivity and efficient release process.
- Collaborated with the backend team to develop backend **RESTful API** with **Node.js**, **TypeScript**, and **PostgreSQL** and maintained seamless frontend to backend integration.

Education

Tunghai University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Sep 2017 - June 2021

National Taiwan Normal University

Chinese Preparatory Program

Sep 2015 - June 2017

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, TypeScript, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Vue, Redux/Redux Toolkit, Vuex, Next.js, TailwindCSS, NestJS, Express, Prisma, Jest, Cypress

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools: Git/Github, Github Actions, Docker, Figma, Postman, Bash, Visual Studio Code

Projects

Order Book Web App: Personal Project

- Implemented React and TypeScript with websocket to develop a real-time app to track order book stock data.
- Utilized TailwindCSS for styling and Redux Toolkit for better global state management solution.

LinkedOut: Personal Project

- Full stack web application to document users profile and work experience inspired by LinkedIn.
- Utilized React, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL to build the application with RTK query to manage application state.

Languages

- English Full Professional Proficiency
- Chinese Professional Working Proficiency
- Indonesian Native Proficiency